## Arsenii Ashukha

Google Scholar / GitHub / Twitter / London, UK / E-mail: ars.ashuha@gmail.com

I work as Senior Research Scientist at Isomorphic Labs, Alphabet subsidiary led by Demis Hassabis, where I develop and train deep learning models for drug descovery. Before joining Iso, I was a machinel learning PhD student at Bayesian Methods Research Group and Samsung AI. You may be familiar with some of my projects: LaMa Inpainting (\*8.4k), PyTorch Ensembles, and Variational Dropout Sparsifies DNN.

Publications scholar.google.com/citations?user=IU-kuP8AAAA (~3k citations)

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2022 - now	Isomorphic Labs Senior Research Scientist (Feb 2024). Research Scientist (Oct 2022). Stealth models for drug design.
2018 - 2022	Samsung Al Lead Research Scientist (2020). Research Scientist (2018). Developed LaMa, an efficient image inpainting model, unceratntiy estimation models and evaluation frameworks. Since 2020, co-led a team, focused on applications of generative models and reinforcement learning.
2016 - 2018	National Research University Higher School of Economics Student Resercher at Bayesian Methods Research Group. Created sparse variational dropout, a compression method for deep learning models, leading to 250x compressio ratio. This position was done in collaboration with Yandex and University of Amsterdam.
Internships	<ul><li>2016 Yandex Deep learning based recommendation system for spotify-like music service.</li><li>2015 Rambler Language models based recommendation systems for news aggregators.</li></ul>
EDUCATION	
2017 - 2022	PhD in Machine Learning, National Research University Higher School of Economics Title: Prior Knowledge for Deep Learning (link). Advisor: Dmitry Vetrov. Committee: Durk Kingma, Karen Ullrich, Jasper Snoek, Yingzhen Li, Sergey Nikolenko.

## **MISCELLANEOUS**

2015 - 2017

2011 - 2015

• **Technical stack:** deep learning, deep neural networks, machine learning, python, numpy, matplotlib, scikit-learn, pandas, bash, git, linux, jax, pytorch, distributed training, dataflow, beam.

BSc in Computer Science, Bauman Moscow State Technical University

MSc in Computer Science, Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology with Distinction

- Code: Research-ready implementations: LaMa Image Inpainting, Multi-GPU SimCLRv1, Ensembles. Simple MVP implementations of ML algorithms: Real NVP normalizing flows, Quantile Regression DQN (Distributional RL), Equivariant GNN
- Programm committee: NeurIPS 2021: outstanding reviewer award, ICML 2020 top-33% highest-scored reviewers
- **Teaching:** Co-author of machine learning textbook in Russian https://education.yandex.ru/handbook/ml, teached machine learning at top-3 Russian universities and yandex scool of data analysis.
- Thesis co-supervision: Alexander Lyzhov (moved to NYU, Deep Ensembles: Analysis and Approaches to Diversification MSc, 2020), Andrei Atanov (moved to EPFL, Effective Learning of Deep Neural Networks Ensembles BSc, 2018, Learning Deep Models with Small Data MSc, 2020), Evgenii Nikishin (moved to Mila, Stability Improvement and Knowledge Transfer in Deep Reinforcement Learning MSc, 2019).
- I hold a Global Talant UK Visa